<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HealthyInfo Of Diabetes</string>

    <string name="diabetes">
        What is Diabetes:

Diabetes is a disease that occurs when your blood glucose,
also called blood sugar, is too high. Blood glucose is your main
source of energy and comes from the food you eat. Insulin, a
hormone made by the pancreas, helps glucose from food get into your
cells to be used for energy. Sometimes your body doesn’t make
enough—or any—insulin or doesn’t use insulin well. Glucose then
stays in your blood and doesn’t reach your cells.

Over time, having too much glucose in your blood can cause health problems.
Although diabetes has no cure, you can take steps to manage your diabetes
and stay healthy.

Sometimes people call diabetes “a touch of sugar” or “borderline diabetes.”
These terms suggest that someone doesn’t really have diabetes or has a less serious
case, but every case of diabetes is serious.

    </string>

    <string name="types_of_diabetes">
        What are the different types of diabetes:

The most common types of diabetes are type 1, type 2, and gestational diabetes.

Type 1 diabetes:

If you have type 1 diabetes, your body does not make insulin. Your immune system
attacks and destroys the cells in your pancreas that make insulin. Type 1 diabetes is
usually diagnosed in children and young adults, although it can appear at any age.
People with type 1 diabetes need to take insulin every day to stay alive.


Type 2 diabetes:

If you have type 2 diabetes, your body does not make or use insulin well. You can
develop type 2 diabetes at any age, even during childhood. However, this type of diabetes
occurs most often in middle-aged and older people. Type 2 is the most common type of diabetes.

Gestational diabetes:

Gestational diabetes develops in some women when they are pregnant. Most of the time,
this type of diabetes goes away after the baby is born. However, if you’ve had gestational
diabetes, you have a greater chance of developing type 2 diabetes later in life. Sometimes
diabetes diagnosed during pregnancy is actually type 2 diabetes.

Other types of diabetes:
Less common types include monogenic diabetes, which is an inherited form of diabetes,
and cystic fibrosis-related diabetes

What health problems can people with diabetes develop:
Over time, high blood glucose leads to problems such as-

	heart disease
	stroke
	kidney disease
	eye problems
	dental disease
	nerve damage
	foot problems


    </string>

    <string name="symptoms_of_diabetes">
        Common symptoms of diabetes:

    The most common signs and symptoms of diabetes are:

    Frequent urination:

  Have you been going to the bathroom to urinate more often recently?
    Do you notice that you spend most of the day going to the toilet? When there
    is too much glucose (sugar) in your blood you will urinate more often.

    If your insulin is ineffective, or not there at all, your kidneys cannot
    filter the glucose back into the blood. The kidneys will take water from your
    blood in order to dilute the glucose - which in turn fills up your bladder.

    Disproportionate thirst:

  If you are urinating more than usual, you will need to replace that lost liquid.
    You will be drinking more than usual. Have you been drinking more than usual lately?

    Intense hunger:

  As the insulin in your blood is not working properly, or is not there at all, and
    your cells are not getting their energy, your body may react by trying to find more
    energy - food. You will become hungry.

    Weight gain:

  This might be the result of the above symptom (intense hunger).

    Unusual weight loss:

  This is more common among people with Diabetes Type 1. As your body is not making
    insulin it will seek out another energy source (the cells aren\'t getting glucose).
    Muscle tissue and fat will be broken down for energy. As Type 1 is of a more sudden
    onset and Type 2 is much more gradual, weight loss is more noticeable with Type 1.

    Increased fatigue:

     If your insulin is not working properly, or is not there at all, glucose will not
    be entering your cells and providing them with energy. This will make you feel tired
    and listless.

    Irritability:

   Irritability can be due to your lack of energy.

    Blurred vision:

     This can be caused by tissue being pulled from your eye lenses. This affects your
    eyes' ability to focus. With proper treatment this can be treated. There are severe
    cases where blindness or prolonged vision problems can occur.

    Cuts and bruises don't heal properly or quickly
    Do you find cuts and bruises take a much longer time than usual to heal? When
    there is more sugar (glucose) in your body, its ability to heal can be undermined.

    More skin and/or yeast infections:

  When there is more sugar in your body, its ability to recover from infections is
    affected. Women with diabetes find it especially difficult to recover from bladder and
    vaginal infections.

    Itchy skin:

   A feeling of itchiness on your skin is sometimes a symptom of diabetes.

    Gums are red and/or swollen - Gums pull away from teeth:

      If your gums are tender, red and/or swollen this could be a sign of diabetes.
    Your teeth could become loose as the gums pull away from them.

    Frequent gum disease/infection:

  As well as the previous gum symptoms, you may experience more frequent gum
    disease and/or gum infections.

    Sexual dysfunction among men:

  If you are over 50 and experience frequent or constant sexual dysfunction
    (erectile dysfunction), it could be a symptom of diabetes.

    </string>

    <string name="conciousness_of_diabetes">
        Consciousness of Diabetes:

Living with a chronic condition like diabetes necessitates the maintaining of a
certain level of consciousness that those without such a condition may not
understand. Diabetes is a mindset, and it’s also a way of life. It isn’t something
that can be turned off on a whim, although many diabetics may want to do just that
from time to time.

The Reality:

 Whether an individual is living with diabetes, Hepatitis C, fibromyalgia, HIV,
an anxiety disorder, or a thyroid condition, the daily reality of that illness, condition,
or syndrome is a constant reminder that you’re different from other people.

Those of us with such conditions live a life wherein our condition or illness may not
define us, but it does indeed offer parameters, limitations, and boundaries that impact
our life in both small and large ways.

Identity:

While we may in some way allow ourselves to be defined by our condition, we also
have other definitions that define us as well. These other aspects of our self-identity
may include father, mother, student, carpenter, nurse, teacher, sister, traveler,
or painter---anything that defines our lives in both positive and negative ways.

At various points in our lives, we may rail against our identity vis-à-vis our illness
or chronic condition, and at other times, we may gain some direct benefit from it
(ie: applying for disability).

Whether you count your condition as part of your identity or not, this is a important
phenomenon and tendency to understand, even if it currently holds no meaning for you.
After all, an adolescent diabetic may view her condition in a much different light
than a diabetic who is celebrating his 50th birthday. It’s perspective and perception
that can inform our identity, and that perspective and perception can change over time.

Thoughtful Living:

 Living with diabetes or another chronic condition indeed necessitates a certain
thoughtfulness and circumspection. Lifestyle choices can have a direct impact on the
trajectory of your diabetes, including, but not limited to, exercise, diet, alcohol
intake, stress levels, sleep habits, and workstyle. And we must also guard against
depression and anxiety,

Whether you resent these apparent restrictions, or you embrace them as par for the
diabetic course, there’s little doubt that your diabetes is on your mind at most
every turn. Diabetes informs many aspects of your life, and if you want to avoid
the negative consequences of poor diabetic control, then that level of conscious
awareness and vigilance needs to remain strong.

Living a high-quality diabetic life is altogether possible, and many do it every day.
When you’re able and willing to embrace the challenge, applying critical thinking and
conscientious attention to the path before you, there’s no doubt that you’ll come out
ahead as your conscientiousness pays vast short- and long-term dividends.

     </string>

    <string name="exercise_and_dietplan">
       Exercise for Diabetes:

Types of exercise for people with diabetes
 The American Diabetes Association recommends two types of physical activity for those
with diabetes:
o	Aerobic exercise and
o	strength training.

Aerobic exercise:

Also known as cardiovascular exercise, aerobic activity helps the body use insulin
more effectively. It brings other benefits too, including:

	stress relief
	 improved circulation
	 reduced risk of heart disease
	 lower blood pressure
	 improved cholesterol levels
	strong bones
	weight management
	 better mood

Examples of aerobic exercises include:
	brisk walking or hiking
	 low-impact aerobic exercise classes
	 Swimming
	 Rowing
	Cycling
	Basketball
	 Dancing
	Skating
	Tennis
	Jogging
	 Tai Chi

How much aerobic activity is needed?

 The Presidents Council on Fitness, Sports and Nutrition recommends:

 30 minutes daily of moderate physical aerobic activity at least 5 times weekly
   This recommendation is for adults aged 18-64. Adults with diabetes should
   also aim to meet this target.

   those with a busy schedule may find it helpful to do several shorter workouts totaling
   30 minutes daily - research suggests that the benefits received are similar to those
   associated with one longer workout.

Strength training:
Strength training, or resistance training, helps lower blood sugar levels and
increases insulin sensitivity. In addition, it increases resting metabolism and
builds stronger bones and muscles, reducing the risk of osteoporosis.

Examples of strength training include:

 1. lifting free weights
   2.   lifting heavy objects, such as bottles of water or canned food
   3.   weight machines
    4.  resistance bands
    5.  exercises that use body weight such as sit-ups, squats, planks, and push-ups
    6.  strength training classes

How much strength training is needed?

Strength training should be undertaken at least twice a week, in addition to
the recommended amount of aerobic activity.


Diet Plan for Diabetes:


What diet is best for diabetes?

Having diabetes does not involve any particularly difficult dietary demands,
and while sugary foods obviously affect blood glucose levels, the diet does not have to
be completely sugar-free.

Dietary concerns vary slightly for people with different types of diabetes.
For people with type 1 diabetes, diet is about managing fluctuations in blood glucose
levels while for people with type 2 diabetes, it is about losing weight and restricting
calorie intake.

For people with type 1 diabetes, the timing of meals is particularly important in terms
of glycemic control and in relation to the effects of insulin injection.

In general, however, a healthy, balanced diet is all that is needed, and the benefits
are not confined to good diabetes management - they also mean good heart health.
A healthy diet typically includes a variety of fruits and vegetables, whole grains,
low-fat dairy products, skinless poultry and fish, nuts and legumes and non-tropical
vegetable oils.

The following are some general dietary tips for a healthy lifestyle:

 1. Eat regularly - avoid the effects on glucose levels of skipping meals or having
delayed meals because of work or long journeys (take healthy snacks with you)

2. Eat vegetables and fruits and eat them in place of high-calorie foods - a variety
of fresh, frozen and canned is good, but avoid high-calorie sauces and food containing
added salt or sugar

3. Whole grains high in fiber are recommended as a healthy source of carbohydrate

4. Eat pulses, a low-fat starchy source of protein and fiber, such as beans,
 lentils, chickpeas and garden peas
5.Reduce intake of saturated and trans fats by having poultry and fish without the skin
and cooked, for example, under the grill, rather than fried

6.Take a similar approach to cooking red meat while reducing intake and looking
for the leanest cuts

 7.Eat fish twice a week or more, but avoid batters and frying - go for oily fish such
as salmon, mackerel, sardine, trout and herring, which are rich sources of omega-3

8.Avoid partially hydrogenated vegetable oils and limit saturated fat and trans
fat - replace them with monounsaturated and polyunsaturated fats

9.Dairy awareness helps reduce fat intake - select skim (fat-free) milk and
low-fat (1%) dairy products, reduce consumption of cheese and butter and swap out
creamy sauces for tomato-based ones

10.Cut back on sugar by avoiding added sugars in drinks and foods - have tea and coffee
without sugar, avoid fruit that is canned in syrup and pay attention to food labels

11.Cut back on salt - prepare foods at home with little or no salt and avoid foods
with high sodium such as processed foods

12.Cut back on portion sizes - be wary of amounts consumed when eating out

 13.Be wary of "diabetic" foods - they are of no particular benefit and can be expensive

 14.Drink alcohol only in moderation - as a guide, no more than one drink a day for women
and no more than two for men.


     </string>

    <string name="address">Address: House-Y-7, Road-1, Chandgaon Residential Area, Block-A, Chittagong</string>
    <string name="phone"> Phone no:01626-159356 </string>

    <string name="address1">Address:Kashem Mansion,Aman Bazar., চট্রগ্রাম - রাঙামাটি-খাগড়াছড়ি মহাসড়ক </string>
    <string name="phone1"> Phone no:01815-622239  </string>

    <string name="address2"> Address:Puraton Girza, West Side Of Laldighi, Deep Tube Well Goli, Chittagong 4000  </string>
    <string name="phone2"> Phone no: 01711-011644  </string>

    <string name="address3">Address:Momin Rd, Chittagong </string>
    <string name="phone3"> Phone no: 01827-023470  </string>

    <string name="address4">Address:Zakir Hossain Road, Khulsi, Chittagong 4212 </string>
    <string name="phone4"> Phone no:316594357  </string>

    <string name="address5">Address:Patiya </string>
    <string name="phone5">  </string>

    <string name="address6"> Address:Fotika Road, Shahjalal Para, Hathazari, Chittagong 4330 </string>
    <string name="phone6">  Phone no:01815-507832  </string>

    <string name="address7">Address:Bandoor Tilla Br, Mofize Sodagor Bari Rd, Chittagong </string>
    <string name="phone7"> Phone no: 01192-040123  </string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps1">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps2">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps3">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps4">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps5">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps6">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps7">Map</string>

</resources>
